<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>James W. Sewall Company and NatureServe assisted by FWS staff</origin><pubdate>20050107</pubdate><title>Cover_Type</title><edition>1</edition><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Old Town, ME</pubplace><publish>James W. Sewall Company</publish></pubinfo><onlink>\\IFW9NCTC-SMCCLA\D$\TEC7112\Moosehorn\Moosehorn.gdb</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>James W. Sewall Company used its standard photointerpretation and ortho-mapping workflow and was assisted by NatureServe in crosswalking to NVC vegetation and wetlands mapping on approximately 115,926 acres across New England.  Refuges include: Nulhegan NWR (VT), Pondicherry NWR (NH), Eastern Mass NWR (MA), Parker River NWR (MA), Rachel Carson NWR (ME), Sunkhaze Meadows NWR (ME), Moosehorn NWR (ME), Aroostook NWR (ME) and several island refuges in Massachusetts.  Aerial photography using color infrared (CIR) film was acquired during the spring and early summer at a scale of 1"=1000? (1:12,000).  Sewall's photointerpreter conducted fieldwork in conjunction with NatureServe and FWS staff to identify signature and establish what would be classified.  Fieldwork was limited due to budgetary constraints, but all but the island refuges were visited - four by Sewall with NatureServe and/or USFW staff accompanying, and the remainder by NatureServe and USFW staff only, who provided detailed feedback to Sewall in the form of annotated maps and GIS data.  For the island refuges, NatureServe and USFW staff provided data and suggested NVC classes.   This shapefile contains the interpeted attributes and has been "crosswalked" with NVC codes (up to 3 per polygon).</abstract><purpose>To provide a spatially accurate photointerpreted classification scheme for use in habitat management planning and as a base for further vegetation mapping in the field.</purpose></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20040501</begdate><enddate>20040630</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><current>Photo Dates</current></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed based on FWS fieldwork - update methodology to be determined by FWS.</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-67.378280</westbc><eastbc>-67.133378</eastbc><northbc>45.159534</northbc><southbc>44.766977</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>NVC</themekt><themekey>Vegetative Cover, NVC</themekey></theme><place><placekt>New England, Wildlife Refuges</placekt><placekey>New England</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None known</accconst><useconst>None known</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Daniel Boss</cntper><cntorg>James W. Sewall Company</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Director, Mappinig Services</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>physical address</addrtype><address>136 Center Street</address><city>Old Town</city><state>ME</state><postal>04468</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>207-827-4456</cntvoice><cntfax>207-827-3641</cntfax><cntemail>dan_boss@jws.com</cntemail><hours>8-5 M-F</hours></cntinfo></ptcontac><native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>The detailed description produced from photointerpretation is code in the "alpha" field.  This data was entered directly from interpreted photos and then was automatically checked by a parsing aml, and components distributed into species, height and crown closure attributes.  This routine ensured that codes were valid.  These codes were then checked  by the original photointerpreter to make sure they were as interpreted.  Map Classes and NVC codes were assigned from tables provided by NatureServe.  For a significant amount of the acreage, this assignment was done in a manner that allowed any unique combinations of NVC association on an individual polygon, determined by fieldwork or other means, to be captured in this deliverable.  In the others, a given map class always has the same set of NVC codes associated with it.  A table accompanying this delivery (crosswalking_approach_by_refuge.xls) indicates on a refuge-by-refuge basis whether NVC assignment was polygon-by-polygon or by map class.  A summary of the codes for the whole area, and by refuge, is available in a separate spreadsheet - mapclass_x_cegl_common_v2.xls.  This spreadsheet can be referred to for assessment of completeness of attribution.  The pivot table tab of this spreadsheet provides an easy way to review the NVC codes by map class for each refuge.</attraccr></attracc><logic>Photo Interpretation with limited fieldwork.  Transfer of polygons from photo to GIS coverage using orthorectification technique to transfer the photo-interpreted lines.  Crosswalking with NVC codes followed by detailed checking by NatureServe and Sewall.</logic><complete>
Covers all lands within the boundaries shown in project boundary coverage provided by FWS - FWS_BND_ALL5.

Revisions made by Sewall 1/7/05 to Pondicherry due to changed boundary file - extended cover types by additional photointerpretation on three photos and assigned map class based what had been assigned in other parts of the same refuge.
</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Based on method used, horizontal position of vegetation polygons should meet national map accuracy standards for the scale of the photos (1:12000), that is +/- 25 feet 90% of the time.  Accuracy was verified by overlay on available orthophotos.  Many vegetation cover boundaries are subjective - positional accuracy verification was performed on clearly defined type boundaries.</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>N/A</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>James W Sewall</origin><pubdate>20041227</pubdate><title>Northeast National Wildlife Refuge Vegetation Classification</title></citeinfo></srccite><srcscale>12000</srcscale><typesrc>Aerial Photography Film, Orthophoto and DEM data from USGS and State of Massachusetts</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><mdattim><sngdate><caldate>20040501</caldate></sngdate><sngdate><caldate>20040630</caldate></sngdate></mdattim></timeinfo><srccurr>20040501</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>NENWRNVC</srccitea><srccontr>Photo-interpretation, mapping, project management.</srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>
1. Aerial Photography
Since the geographic area of the proposed properties covered over 400 miles north to south, the optimal time frame to capture Spring photography varied.  Sewall flew the area of interest in five mobilizations.  With the help of NatureServe and FWS staff, the optimal time for capture of photography for each refuge  (in terms of vegetation development) was  determined.  A FWS contact was designated for each of the six regions.   This contact attended a kickoff meeting held on April 28, 2004 at Sewall's office in Old Town, Maine and acted as local liason for the project to coordinate activities specific to the refuge.

2. Setup - Organizing of Materials, Kickoff Meeting,  Development of Typing Scheme and Database Schema
Sewall provided Maine and Massachusetts digital orthophotos.  USFWS provided orthophotography for Vermont and New Hampshire NWR's as well as NWI wetlands mapping and other relevant ancillary data.   Sewall worked with USFWS and NatureServe to devise a single system for all the refuges so that, insofar as possible, each refuge received the level of detail required for habitat management decisions.

The project kickoff meeting held in Old Town reviewed the proposed plan prior to project startup. At the kickoff meeting the plan for the project was demonstrated by Sewall using data from Petit Manan NWR (completed by Sewall in 2002). Detailed plans for the project, including database schema, were discussed.

The types to be distinguished were briefly discussed for some refuges, along with the requirements of the required photointerpretation codes and type descriptions.  The photointerpretation codes were designed to contain all necessary detail to permit a later conversion ("crosswalk") to Ecological Systems or Alliances/Associations, and to be used by USF&amp;W in labeling maps.

3. Fieldwork with NatureServe Ecologists
The Sewall photo interpreter reviewed the photography and, with the CIR contact prints in hand, engaged in fieldwork with a NatureServe ecologists (and NWR staff, as desired) on a total of four refuges - Great Meadows, Rachel Carson, Moosehorn, and Nulhegan.  This work was designed to identify the Ecological Systems and associated NVCS Alliances/Associations that potentially occur at the refuge and the photo signatures to be delineated. This fieldwork was later supplemented by NatureServe and FWS staff input for Parker River and Rachel Carson (working with color photocopies of the preliminary interpretation).

4. Vegetation and Wetlands Interpretation
Following the fieldwork, the interpreter returned to the Sewall offices in Old Town to apply the typing scheme.  This was done using a Bausch and Lomb SIS 95 stereoscope. Types were labeled on acetates taped to the original color infrared film transparencies.

Rough property limits were transferred to the photographs using boundary information supplied by FWS. Interpretation was done to a .75 acre minimum in the non-forest areas, and a 4 acre minimum in forested areas (although going below these minimums to type obvious conditions of significance frequently occurred). Sewall utilized a descriptive scheme for detailed classification in forest stands, including forest understory interpretation.

5. Mapping Procedures
The method of conversion from photo to map utilized digital terrain data and PCI orthorectification software.  The best available orthophotos (1:5000 in Vermont and Massachusetts, 1:24000 in the other states) and digital elevation data (USGS NED data in VT, NH, and ME; 1:5000 DEM from the Massachusetts orthophoto project for MA) were employed as a basis for the orthorectification.

Up to six ground control points per typed photo were identified on the orthophotos, located on the aerial photo, and marked on the acetate overlay.  Ground control points and cover type lines on the photo overlays were scanned using a MICROTEK color scanner.  The resulting image (in TIFF format) was be orthorectified using PCI software, the lines vectorized and combined into vegetation polygon feature classes using ArcGIS software.

Sewall used a computer routine for checking all photo interpreted labels.  Any missed or invalid labels were automatically detected and flagged on a check map.  The photo interpreter checked and marked this map for any required corrections.  Corrections were made and a completed GIS coverage created.  After all areas were mapped and all quality control checks were complete, the photointerpreted vegetation polygon layer was created.

The data were compiled in ArcInfo 8.3 coverage format and delivered in this format as well as in shapefile format.  Ownership boundary lines were based on the shapefiles provided by USFWS to Sewall at the beginning of the project.  The GIS coverages were projected to UTM, NAD83 datum, zone 19, meters, for delivery to USFWS.  FGDC-compliant metadata was provided describing the data sources and attribute-coding scheme.

6. Deliverables
- ArcGIS 8.3 vegetation cover types.  The GIS coverage and shapefiles (this file) were delivered to USFWS on CD-ROM.
- Aerial Photography - CIR, 1:12,000 - one set of contact prints.
- A complete set of photogrammetric scans was also requested and delivered.
</procdesc><procdate>20040430</procdate></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused>P:\43710L_NWRcov\trans\to_fws\deliv_20050107\gis_combined\shapefiles\nenwrveg.shp.xml</srcused></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused>D:\43710L_NE_NWR\to_fws\deliv_20051103\nenwrveg05all_polygon.shp.xml</srcused></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused>D:\43710L_NE_NWR\work_finalrevs\shapes\nenwrveg05_v3_polygon</srcused></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused>D:\43710L_NE_NWR\to_fws\deliv_20051115\nenwrveg05_v3_polygon</srcused></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\KKlinger\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml64.tmp</srcused><date>20080922</date><time>16130800</time></procstep><procstep><procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused>D:\TEC7112_Working\Metadata\Cover_Type.xml</srcused><procdate>20090407</procdate><proctime>11265800</proctime></procstep></lineage><cloud>0%</cloud></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><esriterm Name="Favorite_Species"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom code="4" Sync="TRUE"></efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">0</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.000100</absres><ordres>0.000100</ordres></coordrep><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys><vertdef><altsys><altenc>Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc><altres>0.000100</altres></altsys></vertdef></spref><eainfo><detailed Name="Favorite_Species"><attr><attrlabl>COMMENTS</attrlabl><attrdef>Any comments from field visits</attrdef><attrdefs>NatureServe</attrdefs><attalias Sync="TRUE">COMMENTS</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">100</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><enttyp><enttypl>Cover_Type</enttypl><enttypd>Photo interpreted vegetation cover polygons with detailed forest type descriptions and map classes translatable into National Vegetation Classification alliances and/or ecological systems.</enttypd><enttypds>James W Sewall</enttypds><enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">0</enttypc></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl><attrdef>Area in Sq. Meters</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Area in floating point numbers.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">AREA</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl><attrdef>Perimeter in Meters</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Perimeter of polygon in floating point.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">PERIMETER</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>NENWRVEG05</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">NENWRVEG05</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>NENWRVEG_1</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">NENWRVEG_1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>NWRUNIT</attrlabl><attrdef>FWS code for units</attrdef><attrdefs>USFWS</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>None provided</codesetn><codesets>USFWS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">NWRUNIT</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">3</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>NWRNAME</attrlabl><attrdef>FWS code retained from original boundary file</attrdef><attrdefs>USFWS</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>None provided</codesetn><codesets>USFWS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">NWRNAME</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">3</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>ACREAGE</attrlabl><attrdef>Calculated as AREA (internal variable maintained in square meters) * .0002471054.</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Acreage in floating point numbers.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">ACREAGE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>ALPHA</attrlabl><attrdef>Code used by photo interpreter to describe land cover</attrdef><attrdefs>JWS</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Combination of codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">ALPHA</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>OS1</attrlabl><attrdef>Primary overstory species component</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Species codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OS1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>OS2</attrlabl><attrdef>Secondary overstory species component</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Species codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OS2</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>OHGT</attrlabl><attrdef>Average height of overstory components</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Height codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OHGT</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>ODEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Average density (crown closure) of overstory components</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Density codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">ODEN</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>OS3</attrlabl><attrdef>Tertiary speies in overstory stand component</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Species codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OS3</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>US1</attrlabl><attrdef>Primary understory species component</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Species codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">US1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>US2</attrlabl><attrdef>Secondary understory species component</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Species codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">US2</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>UHGT</attrlabl><attrdef>Average understory height</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Height codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">UHGT</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>UDEN</attrlabl><attrdef>Average understory density (crown closure)</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Density codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">UDEN</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>US3</attrlabl><attrdef>Tertiary understory species component</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Combination of codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">US3</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LANDUSE</attrlabl><attrdef>Non-forest type code</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Combination of codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">LANDUSE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>ULANDUSE</attrlabl><attrdef>Non-forest type represented under a forest canopy, if any</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>combination of codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">ULANDUSE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>OSTORY</attrlabl><attrdef>Combination of all components of overstory group</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Combination of codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OSTORY</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>USTORY</attrlabl><attrdef>Combination of all components of understory group</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Species codes listed in spp_list_rev8.xls (separate from this metadata)</codesetn><codesets>James W Sewall</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">USTORY</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">8</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>CHK</attrlabl><attrdef>Attribute used in internal quality check at JWS</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>OK</edomv><edomvd>Checked in internal JWS process and passes</edomvd><edomvds>James W Sewall</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>NG</edomv><edomvd>Does not pass JWS quality check</edomvd><edomvds>James W Sewall</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">CHK</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>MODIFIER</attrlabl><attrdef>Code to modify a forested stand to indicate wet/floodplain or to distinguish forest land that is in an early successional state from woodland.</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>W</edomv><edomvd>Wetland</edomvd><edomvds>James W Sewall</edomvds></edom><edom><edomv>F</edomv><edomvd>Forestland</edomvd><edomvds>James W Sewall</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">MODIFIER</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>MAP_CLASS</attrlabl><attrdef>Letter abbreviation for photointerpreted map class which will be used to crosswalk to the NVC code</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Codes listed in separate map_class code table nenwr_map_class.xls</codesetn><codesets>NatureServe, summarized by JWS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">MAP_CLASS</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">5</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>UNIQ_ID</attrlabl><attrdef>Unique polygon ID populated by Sewall at delivery with the originating coverage polygon's unique polygon number - to be used for polygon identifier in field checking/correction.</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated (copy of first item).</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">UNIQ_ID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>MAP_CLAS_F</attrlabl><attrdef>Alternative field-based map class</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Codes listed in separate map_class code table nenwr_map_class.xls</codesetn><codesets>NatureServe, summarized by JWS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">MAP_CLAS_F</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">5</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>MAPCLASS_N</attrlabl><attrdef>Full descriptive name of map class</attrdef><attrdefs>James W Sewall</attrdefs><attrdomv><codesetd><codesetn>Name vales for codes listed in separate map_class code table nenwr_map_class.xls</codesetn><codesets>NatureServe, summarized by JWS</codesets></codesetd></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">MAPCLASS_N</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">30</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>CEGL_1</attrlabl><attrdef>First association code</attrdef><attrdefs>NatureServe crosswalk tables</attrdefs><attalias Sync="TRUE">CEGL_1</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>CEGL_2</attrlabl><attrdef>Second association code</attrdef><attrdefs>NatureServe crosswalk tables</attrdefs><attalias Sync="TRUE">CEGL_2</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>CEGL_3</attrlabl><attrdef>Third association code</attrdef><attrdefs>NatureServe crosswalk tables</attrdefs><attalias Sync="TRUE">CEGL_3</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>ECOLSYS_CO</attrlabl><attrdef>Ecological system code</attrdef><attrdefs>NatureServe crosswalk tables - northern refuges only</attrdefs><attalias Sync="TRUE">ECOLSYS_CO</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl><attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape_Area</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape_Leng</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape_Leng</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>LandCover</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">LandCover</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">30</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">OHGT_2</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">OHGT_2</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Single</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">13</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr></detailed></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>USFWS</cntorg><cntper>Jennifer Casey, Umbagog NWR</cntper></cntorgp><cntaddr><addrtype>Lake Umbagog NWR</addrtype><address>P.O. Box 280</address><city>Errol</city><state>NH</state><postal>03579</postal><country>USA</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>603-482-3415</cntvoice></cntinfo></distrib><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>Unknown</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>ISO 9660</formname><transize>10.358</transize></digtinfo><digtopt><offoptn><offmedia>CD-ROM</offmedia><recfmt>ISO 9660</recfmt></offoptn></digtopt></digform><fees>Unknown</fees></stdorder></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20090410</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>James W. Sewall Company</cntorg><cntper>Daniel Boss</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Director, Mapping Services</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>136 Center Street</addrtype><city>Old Town</city><state>Maine</state><postal>04401</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>207-827-4456</cntvoice><cntfax>207-827-3641</cntfax><cntemail>dan_boss@jws.com</cntemail><hours>8-5 M-F (Eastern Time Zone)</hours></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo><mdLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA"/></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004"/></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv><mdContact><rpIndName>Daniel Boss</rpIndName><rpOrgName>James W. Sewall Company</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Director, Mapping Services</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>207-827-4456</voiceNum><faxNum>207-827-3641</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><city>Old Town</city><adminArea>Maine</adminArea><postCode>04401</postCode><eMailAdd>dan_boss@jws.com</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntHours>8-5 M-F (Eastern Time Zone)</cntHours></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></mdContact><mdDateSt>20180424</mdDateSt><mdStanName>ArcGIS Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer>1.0</mdStanVer><distInfo><distributor><distorCont><rpIndName>Jennifer Casey, Umbagog NWR</rpIndName><rpOrgName>USFWS</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>603-482-3415</voiceNum></cntPhone><cntAddress><delPoint>P.O. Box 280</delPoint><city>Errol</city><adminArea>NH</adminArea><postCode>03579</postCode><country>US</country></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="005"/></role></distorCont><distorOrdPrc><resFees>Unknown</resFees></distorOrdPrc><distorFormat><formatName>ISO 9660</formatName></distorFormat><distorTran><transSize>10.358</transSize><offLineMed><medName><MedNameCd value="001"/></medName><medFormat><MedFormCd value="004"/></medFormat></offLineMed></distorTran></distributor><distTranOps><onLineSrc><linkage>\\IFW9NCTC-SMCCLA\D$\TEC7112\Moosehorn\Moosehorn.gdb</linkage></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transSize></distTranOps><distFormat><formatName>File Geodatabase Feature Class</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Cover_Type</resTitle><date><pubDate>2005-01-07</pubDate></date><resEd>1</resEd><citRespParty><rpOrgName>James W. Sewall Company and NatureServe assisted by FWS staff</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty><citRespParty><rpOrgName>James W. Sewall Company</rpOrgName><rpCntInfo><cntAddress><delPoint>Old Town, ME</delPoint></cntAddress></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="010"/></role></citRespParty><presForm><PresFormCd value="005"/></presForm><presForm><fgdcGeoform>vector digital data</fgdcGeoform></presForm></idCitation><idAbs>James W. Sewall Company used its standard photointerpretation and ortho-mapping workflow and was assisted by NatureServe in crosswalking to NVC vegetation and wetlands mapping on approximately 115,926 acres across New England. Refuges include: Nulhegan NWR (VT), Pondicherry NWR (NH), Eastern Mass NWR (MA), Parker River NWR (MA), Rachel Carson NWR (ME), Sunkhaze Meadows NWR (ME), Moosehorn NWR (ME), Aroostook NWR (ME) and several island refuges in Massachusetts. Aerial photography using color infrared (CIR) film was acquired during the spring and early summer at a scale of 1"=1000? (1:12,000). Sewall's photointerpreter conducted fieldwork in conjunction with NatureServe and FWS staff to identify signature and establish what would be classified. Fieldwork was limited due to budgetary constraints, but all but the island refuges were visited - four by Sewall with NatureServe and/or USFW staff accompanying, and the remainder by NatureServe and USFW staff only, who provided detailed feedback to Sewall in the form of annotated maps and GIS data. For the island refuges, NatureServe and USFW staff provided data and suggested NVC classes. This shapefile contains the interpeted attributes and has been "crosswalked" with NVC codes (up to 3 per polygon).</idAbs><idPurp>To provide a spatially accurate photointerpreted classification scheme for use in habitat management planning and as a base for further vegetation mapping in the field.</idPurp><idStatus><ProgCd value="001"/></idStatus><idPoC><rpIndName>Daniel Boss</rpIndName><rpOrgName>James W. Sewall Company</rpOrgName><rpPosName>Director, Mappinig Services</rpPosName><rpCntInfo><cntPhone><voiceNum>207-827-4456</voiceNum><faxNum>207-827-3641</faxNum></cntPhone><cntAddress addressType="physical"><delPoint>136 Center Street</delPoint><city>Old Town</city><adminArea>ME</adminArea><postCode>04468</postCode><country>US</country><eMailAdd>dan_boss@jws.com</eMailAdd></cntAddress><cntHours>8-5 M-F</cntHours></rpCntInfo><role><RoleCd value="007"/></role></idPoC><resMaint/><placeKeys><keyword>New England</keyword><thesaName><resTitle>New England, Wildlife Refuges</resTitle></thesaName></placeKeys><themeKeys><keyword>Vegetative Cover</keyword><keyword>NVC</keyword><thesaName><resTitle>NVC</resTitle></thesaName></themeKeys><searchKeys><keyword>New England</keyword><keyword>Vegetative Cover</keyword><keyword>NVC</keyword></searchKeys><resConst><LegConsts><useLimit>Unknown</useLimit><othConsts>None known</othConsts></LegConsts></resConst><resConst><Consts><useLimit>None known</useLimit></Consts></resConst><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001"/></spatRpType><dataLang><languageCode value="eng"/><countryCode value="USA"/></dataLang><envirDesc> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5.0.6491</envirDesc><dataExt><exDesc>Photo Dates</exDesc><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp><TM_Period><tmBegin>2004-05-01</tmBegin><tmEnd>2004-06-30</tmEnd></TM_Period></exTemp></TempExtent></tempEle><geoEle/></dataExt><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox><westBL>-67.37828</westBL><eastBL>-67.133378</eastBL><southBL>44.766977</southBL><northBL>45.159534</northBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><exTypeCode>1</exTypeCode><westBL>-67.378280</westBL><eastBL>-67.133378</eastBL><northBL>45.159534</northBL><southBL>44.766977</southBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt></dataIdInfo><dqInfo><dqScope><scpLvl><ScopeCd value="005"/></scpLvl></dqScope><report type="DQConcConsis"><measDesc>Photo Interpretation with limited fieldwork. Transfer of polygons from photo to GIS coverage using orthorectification technique to transfer the photo-interpreted lines. Crosswalking with NVC codes followed by detailed checking by NatureServe and Sewall.</measDesc></report><report type="DQCompOm"><measDesc>Covers all lands within the boundaries shown in project boundary coverage provided by FWS - FWS_BND_ALL5. Revisions made by Sewall 1/7/05 to Pondicherry due to changed boundary file - extended cover types by additional photointerpretation on three photos and assigned map class based what had been assigned in other parts of the same refuge.</measDesc></report><report type="DQQuanAttAcc"><measDesc>The detailed description produced from photointerpretation is code in the "alpha" field. This data was entered directly from interpreted photos and then was automatically checked by a parsing aml, and components distributed into species, height and crown closure attributes. This routine ensured that codes were valid. These codes were then checked by the original photointerpreter to make sure they were as interpreted. Map Classes and NVC codes were assigned from tables provided by NatureServe. For a significant amount of the acreage, this assignment was done in a manner that allowed any unique combinations of NVC association on an individual polygon, determined by fieldwork or other means, to be captured in this deliverable. In the others, a given map class always has the same set of NVC codes associated with it. A table accompanying this delivery (crosswalking_approach_by_refuge.xls) indicates on a refuge-by-refuge basis whether NVC assignment was polygon-by-polygon or by map class. A summary of the codes for the whole area, and by refuge, is available in a separate spreadsheet - mapclass_x_cegl_common_v2.xls. This spreadsheet can be referred to for assessment of completeness of attribution. The pivot table tab of this spreadsheet provides an easy way to review the NVC codes by map class for each refuge.</measDesc></report><report type="DQAbsExtPosAcc" dimension="horizontal"><measDesc>Based on method used, horizontal position of vegetation polygons should meet national map accuracy standards for the scale of the photos (1:12000), that is +/- 25 feet 90% of the time. Accuracy was verified by overlay on available orthophotos. Many vegetation cover boundaries are subjective - positional accuracy verification was performed on clearly defined type boundaries.</measDesc></report><report type="DQAbsExtPosAcc" dimension="vertical"><measDesc>N/A</measDesc></report><dataLineage><prcStep><stepDesc>1. Aerial Photography Since the geographic area of the proposed properties covered over 400 miles north to south, the optimal time frame to capture Spring photography varied. Sewall flew the area of interest in five mobilizations. With the help of NatureServe and FWS staff, the optimal time for capture of photography for each refuge (in terms of vegetation development) was determined. A FWS contact was designated for each of the six regions. This contact attended a kickoff meeting held on April 28, 2004 at Sewall's office in Old Town, Maine and acted as local liason for the project to coordinate activities specific to the refuge. 2. Setup - Organizing of Materials, Kickoff Meeting, Development of Typing Scheme and Database Schema Sewall provided Maine and Massachusetts digital orthophotos. USFWS provided orthophotography for Vermont and New Hampshire NWR's as well as NWI wetlands mapping and other relevant ancillary data. Sewall worked with USFWS and NatureServe to devise a single system for all the refuges so that, insofar as possible, each refuge received the level of detail required for habitat management decisions. The project kickoff meeting held in Old Town reviewed the proposed plan prior to project startup. At the kickoff meeting the plan for the project was demonstrated by Sewall using data from Petit Manan NWR (completed by Sewall in 2002). Detailed plans for the project, including database schema, were discussed. The types to be distinguished were briefly discussed for some refuges, along with the requirements of the required photointerpretation codes and type descriptions. The photointerpretation codes were designed to contain all necessary detail to permit a later conversion ("crosswalk") to Ecological Systems or Alliances/Associations, and to be used by USF&amp;W in labeling maps. 3. Fieldwork with NatureServe Ecologists The Sewall photo interpreter reviewed the photography and, with the CIR contact prints in hand, engaged in fieldwork with a NatureServe ecologists (and NWR staff, as desired) on a total of four refuges - Great Meadows, Rachel Carson, Moosehorn, and Nulhegan. This work was designed to identify the Ecological Systems and associated NVCS Alliances/Associations that potentially occur at the refuge and the photo signatures to be delineated. This fieldwork was later supplemented by NatureServe and FWS staff input for Parker River and Rachel Carson (working with color photocopies of the preliminary interpretation). 4. Vegetation and Wetlands Interpretation Following the fieldwork, the interpreter returned to the Sewall offices in Old Town to apply the typing scheme. This was done using a Bausch and Lomb SIS 95 stereoscope. Types were labeled on acetates taped to the original color infrared film transparencies. Rough property limits were transferred to the photographs using boundary information supplied by FWS. Interpretation was done to a .75 acre minimum in the non-forest areas, and a 4 acre minimum in forested areas (although going below these minimums to type obvious conditions of significance frequently occurred). Sewall utilized a descriptive scheme for detailed classification in forest stands, including forest understory interpretation. 5. Mapping Procedures The method of conversion from photo to map utilized digital terrain data and PCI orthorectification software. The best available orthophotos (1:5000 in Vermont and Massachusetts, 1:24000 in the other states) and digital elevation data (USGS NED data in VT, NH, and ME; 1:5000 DEM from the Massachusetts orthophoto project for MA) were employed as a basis for the orthorectification. Up to six ground control points per typed photo were identified on the orthophotos, located on the aerial photo, and marked on the acetate overlay. Ground control points and cover type lines on the photo overlays were scanned using a MICROTEK color scanner. The resulting image (in TIFF format) was be orthorectified using PCI software, the lines vectorized and combined into vegetation polygon feature classes using ArcGIS software. Sewall used a computer routine for checking all photo interpreted labels. Any missed or invalid labels were automatically detected and flagged on a check map. The photo interpreter checked and marked this map for any required corrections. Corrections were made and a completed GIS coverage created. After all areas were mapped and all quality control checks were complete, the photointerpreted vegetation polygon layer was created. The data were compiled in ArcInfo 8.3 coverage format and delivered in this format as well as in shapefile format. Ownership boundary lines were based on the shapefiles provided by USFWS to Sewall at the beginning of the project. The GIS coverages were projected to UTM, NAD83 datum, zone 19, meters, for delivery to USFWS. FGDC-compliant metadata was provided describing the data sources and attribute-coding scheme. 6. Deliverables - ArcGIS 8.3 vegetation cover types. The GIS coverage and shapefiles (this file) were delivered to USFWS on CD-ROM. - Aerial Photography - CIR, 1:12,000 - one set of contact prints. - A complete set of photogrammetric scans was also requested and delivered.</stepDesc><stepDateTm>2004-04-30</stepDateTm></prcStep><dataSource><srcDesc>Photo-interpretation, mapping, project management.</srcDesc><srcMedName><MedNameCd value="029"/></srcMedName><srcScale><rfDenom>12000</rfDenom></srcScale><srcCitatn><resTitle>Northeast National Wildlife Refuge Vegetation Classification</resTitle><resAltTitle>NENWRNVC</resAltTitle><date><pubDate>2004-12-27</pubDate></date><citRespParty><rpOrgName>James W Sewall</rpOrgName><role><RoleCd value="006"/></role></citRespParty></srcCitatn><srcExt><exDesc>20040501</exDesc><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp><TM_Instant><tmPosition>2004-06-30</tmPosition></TM_Instant></exTemp></TempExtent></tempEle><tempEle><TempExtent><exTemp><TM_Instant><tmPosition>2004-05-01</tmPosition></TM_Instant></exTemp></TempExtent></tempEle></srcExt></dataSource></dataLineage></dqInfo><mdHrLvName>dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="26919"/><idCodeSpace>EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion>6.13(3.0.1)</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><geometObjs Name="Favorite_Species"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">0</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></TopoLevCd></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><Esri><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">Favorite_Species</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><nativeExtBox><westBL Sync="TRUE">628325.728000</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">646718.612000</eastBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">4958737.012000</southBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">5001969.500000</northBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></nativeExtBox><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\IFW9NCTC-MRICHA\D$\CSP7102\MH\Shapefiles\Favorite_Species.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation><itemSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</itemSize></itemProps><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Meter (1.000000)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_19N</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/2.0.0'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;NAD_1983_UTM_Zone_19N&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Transverse_Mercator&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,500000.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-69.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Scale_Factor&amp;quot;,0.9996],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Meter&amp;quot;,1.0],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;,26919]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-5120900&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-9998100&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;450445547.3910538&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;26919&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;LatestWKID&gt;26919&lt;/LatestWKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef></DataProperties><SyncDate>20180504</SyncDate><SyncTime>09593900</SyncTime><ModDate>20180504</ModDate><ModTime>09593900</ModTime></Esri></metadata>
